### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

With a solid education and 1+ years of successful work experience in Big-data analytics and Artificial intelligence, experience in regression modelling, predictive data modelling, and quantitative data analysis with statistical modelling, quantitative analysis, machine learning, deep learning, time series analysis, NLP, social media analysis and fraud detection to deliver insights and implement an action-oriented solution to complex business problems.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **RENNES SCHOOL OF BUSINESS**

RENNES, FRANCE

MSc/data and business analytics

JANUARY. 2019-OCTOBER. 2020

### INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING (INSOFE)

HYDERABAD, INDIA

PGP certification/ BIG DATA OPTIMIZATION AND ANALYTICS

FEBRUARY.2018-DECEMBER. 2018

• Won 600 EUR winning price in Fraud detection hackathon

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Skoleom Platform PARIS, FRANCE

Data scientist/ Contract APRIL. 2021– OCTOBER. 2021

 Developed real-time Al algorithm to detect fashion products from videos and caption them using Python and YOLO v5 algorithm.

## Rennes School of business

PARIS, FRANCE

Research assistant/Contract

JANUARY. 2021- MARCH. 2021

• Developed a machine learning and deep learning model with weather statistical behaviour to forecast weather temperature using Python, and SQL.

## Institut supérieur d'électronique (ISEP)

**PARIS, FRANCE** 

Big data and machine learning /Intern

JANUARY. 2020- JUNE. 2020

• Implemented a multilayer weather forecast predictive ensemble machine learning and deep learning model using statistical analysis, predictive modeling, with Python, Spark, Hive, SparkSQL to improve the model scalability and accuracy. This research has been funded by "Conseil Regional de l'Ile de France".

# **RENNES SCHOOL OF BUSINESS**

RENNES, FRANCE

Research assistant/Contract

March. 2019- August. 2019

- Developed AI patent data on NBER patent Data Using Python, SQL, Hadoop for big data with Text mining, text analysis, and NLP.
- Implemented new variables on patents related to Artificial Intelligence to the list of companies on NBER data.

INSOFE HYDERABAD, INDIA

Research in AI /Intern

JULY. 2018 - SEPTEMBER. 2018

• Classified the movement of international Crude oil prices using Python, SQL with statistical analysis & modeling, text analysis, topic modeling, NLP, LSTM and sentiment analysis from daily international news articles and Indicators.

# **LANGUAGES**

Hindi 1 (Native); English 2 (Bilingual); French 3 (Basic)

**SKILLS** 

## **Professional Skills**

- Python, R, SQL, Linux, Social media analysis, quantitative data analysis, predictive data modeling, time series analysis, statistical modeling, machine learning, deep learning, text analysis, Computer vision, object detection, NLP, research, Visualization.
- Big-Data analytics, API, Keras, Scikit-learn, Spark, Hadoop, Docker.

### **Soft Skills**

• Analytical thinking, Teamwork, Interpersonal /Communication skills, Problem-solving, good presentation skills